Barry Faulkner
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Barry Faulkner papers
circa 1858-1973
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Faulkner, Barry
2.3 linear feet
The papers of muralist, painter, and teacher Barry Faulkner measure 2.3 linear feet and date from circa 1858-1973. Faulkner's career; his relationships with family, friends, and fellow-artists; and his thoughts on art and artists are documented in biographical materials, correspondence, writings, sketchbooks, five diaries, two photograph albums and photographs, and one scrapbook. Correspondents include family members, Witter Bynner, Ann and Eric Gugler, Leon Kroll, Isabel Manship, James Johnson Sweeney, and others.
Provenance
The collection was donated by Francis Faulkner, Barry Faulkner's nephew, in 1974.
Related Material
Found in the Nancy Douglas Bowditch papers at the Archives of American Art is correspondence, photographs, and printed materials related to Barry Faulkner. The Library of Congress, Manuscript Division also holds a small collection of Barry Faulkner's papers. Additional correspondence from Faulkner is found in the papers of Witter Bynner at the University of New Mexico and at Harvard University.
Alternative Forms Available
The bulk of this collection was digitized in 2009 and is available via the Archives of American Art's website. Materials which have not been scanned include photographs of artwork, a few essays and writings by others, oversized architectural drawings, and several publications not related to Faulkner's art or life.
Restrictions on Access
The bulk of this collection has been digitized and is available online via AAA's website.
Biographical Note
Francis Barrett Faulkner was born on July 12, 1881 in Keene, New Hampshire. He attended Phillips Exeter Academy and went on to study at Harvard College. Around this same time, Faulkner began an apprenticeship with his cousin and painter Abbott Handerson Thayer and painter George de Forest Brush. He also met sculptors James Earle Fraser and Augustus Saint-Gaudens, both of whom became Faulkner's lifelong friends.
In 1901, Faulkner traveled to Italy for the first time with Thayer and his family. He returned to New York in 1902 and studied at the Art Students League and Chase School. He also completed illustration work for Century magazine.
In 1907, Faulkner won the Rome Prize Fellowship from the American Academy in Rome. shortly thereafter, he left to study in Italy for three years, studying with George de Forest Brush and befriending sculptor Paul Manship. Upon his return in 1910, he started working on his first mural, commissioned by the wife of railroad executive E.H. Harriman. Having found his niche, Faulkner continued taking mural commissions until his career was interrupted by World War I and his service in the camouflage section of the army. Shortly after the war, he completed a mural for the marine headquarters in Quantico, Virginia.
Between 1923-1924, Faulkner worked in collaboration with Eric Gugler and Paul Manship to create the American Academy in Rome war memorial. Also following the war, Faulkner completed murals for the Eastman School of Music in 1922, the Rockefeller Center in 1932, and the National Archives in 1936. That same year, Faulkner bought and refurbished a house named "The Bounty" in Keene, New Hampshire, and built a studio nearby. In 1930, he was elected as a trustee of the American Academy in Rome.
During the 1940s, Faulkner created murals for numerous public buildings and sites around New Hampshire including the Senate Chambers in Concord, the Elliot Community Hospital, Keene National Bank, and the Cheshire County Savings Bank in Keene. During his final decades, Faulkner wrote an unpublished manuscript on the history of art in the Connecticut River Valley entitled A Neighborhood of Artists, and his posthumously published memoirs, Sketches of an Artist's Life. Faulkner died in 1966, in Keene, New Hampshire.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of muralist, painter, and teacher Barry Faulkner measure 2.3 linear feet and date from circa 1858-1973. Faulkner's career; his relationships with family, friends, and fellow-artists; and his thoughts on art and artists are documented in biographical materials, correspondence, writings, sketchbooks, five diaries, photograph albums and photographs, and one scrapbook.
Biographical materials include biographical sketches, awards, and records documenting Faulkner's military service. Also found are a list of medications, a list of Faulkner's writings, party guest lists, an address book, a calendar, and materials related to the posthumous publication of Sketches From an Artist's Life. Of special interest are oversized architectural drawings by Eric Gugler for Faulkner's Keene, New Hampshire house.
Correspondence includes letters from Faulkner's friends, family, fellow artists, and art organizations and institutions. Faulkner's correspondence with his parents document his 1900-1901 trip to Italy with the Thayer family. Of special interest is his correspondence with writer Witter Bynner about Faulkner's daily life in New Hampshire, his travels through Europe, his artistic practice and career, Bynner's writings, his opinions on artistic and literary works, and his service in World War One. Many of the letters to Bynner include sketches by Faulkner of Abbott Handerson Thayer, Rockwell Kent, Augustus Saint-Gaudens, Homer Saint-Gaudens, George de Forest Brush, Kahlil Gibran, and Mark Twain. Additional correspondents include sculptor Frances Grimes, architect Eric Gugler, painter Leon Kroll, and museum director James Johnson Sweeney.
Faulkner's writings are about art, artists, and the New Hampshire art community. Found are essays on Gifford Beal, George de Forest Brush, James Earle Fraser, Harriet Hosmer, Paul Manship, Charles Adams Platt, Hiram Powers, Edward Willis Redfield, Joseph Lindon Smith, Mary Lawrence Tonetti, Mark Twain, Lawrence Grant White, and Mahonri Young. Other writings discuss Faulkner's mural commissions, various aspects of New Hampshire history, and the history of the Dublin and Cornish art colonies whose inhabitants included George de Forest Brush, Augustus Saint-Gaudens, and Abbott Handerson Thayer. Of special interest is a manuscript for Faulkner's posthumously published memoir Sketches From an Artist's Life, and an unpublished manuscript titled A Neighborhood of Artists about the history and culture of the Connecticut River Valley.
Four sketchbooks by Faulkner contain drawings of landscapes, city scenes, architecture, people, nature, and studies of artwork by others. Also found are two loose sketches.
Five diaries document Faulkner's 1922-1924 trip through Europe, Africa, and Asia including stops in France, Italy, Egypt, and Turkey. Diaries record Faulkner's thoughts on architecture, tourist sites, and travel amenities. Found is one diary from 1956 that discusses social events, the Saint-Gaudens Memorial, the MacDowell Colony of artists, and various artists including Gifford Beal, Maxfield Parrish, Paul Manship, and Eric Gugler.
The bulk of printed material consists of clippings which document published writings by Faulkner, obituaries and published rememberances of Faulkner, local events in Keene, New Hampshire, and reproductions of Faulkner's artwork. Also found are exhibition catalogs of other artists, an announcement of Faulklner's death from the American Academy of Arts and Letters, and a publication illustrated with reproductions of Faulkner's murals for the National Archives.
Photographs include formal and informal images of Faulkner throughout his life, and photographs of his family and friends, his studio, and reproductions of his artwork. Also included are two photograph albums, one of which contains photographs of Faulkner during his youth and one that contains photographs primarily from the 1930s of Faulkner's Keene, New Hampshire house, himself, and his friends and family.
The collection also includes a scrapbook prepared for Faulkner's seventieth birthday containing photographs, cards, telegrams, and placecards with hand drawn illustrations which show the "taste and characteristics" of Faulkner.
Index Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following index terms.
Subjects:
Brush, George de Forest, 1855-1941; Beal, Gifford,1879-1956; Fraser, James Earle,1876-1953; Gibran, Kahlil, 1922-; Hosmer, Harriet; Kent, Rockwell, 1882-1971; Manship, Paul, 1885-1966; Parrish, Maxfield, 1870-1966; Platt, Charles A., (Charles Adams),1861-1933; Powers, Hiram, 1805-1873; Redfield, Edward Willis, 1869-1965; Smith, Joseph Lindon, 1863-1950; Saint-Gaudens, Augustus, 1848-1907; Saint-Gaudens, Homer B., 1880-; Thayer, Abbott Handerson, 1849-1921; Tonetti, Mary Lawrence; Twain, Mark, 1835-1910; White, Lawrence Grant; Young, Mahonri Sharp, 1911-; MacDowell Colony
Subjects-Topical:
Artists' studios in art; Artists' studios -- New Hampshire; Artist colonies -- New Hampshire -- Cornish; Artist colonies -- New Hampshire -- Dublin; Educators -- New Hampshire; Mural painting and decoration -- 20th century -- United States; Artists -- New Hampshire; Painting, Modern --20th century -- New Hampshire -- Keene; Muralists -- New Hampshire -- Keene; Painters -- New Hampshire -- Keene; World War, 1914-1918; Artist colonies -- New Hampshire -- Peterborough
Subjects-Geographical:
New Hampshire
Types of Materials:
Photograph albums; Photographs; Diaries; Travel Diaries; Writings; Scrapbooks; Sketchbooks; Sketches
Names:
Bynner, Witter, 1881-1968; Grimes, Frances, 1869-1963; Gugler, Eric, 1889-1974; Kroll, Leon, 1884-1974; Sweeney, James Johnson, 1900-
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into 8 series:
Series 1: Biographical Materials, 1914-1971 (Box 1, 3, RD1; 13 folders)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1900-1973 (Box 1; 0.5 linear feet)
Series 3: Writings, 1912-1966 (Boxes 1-2; 1.0 linear foot)
Series 4: Sketchbooks and Sketches, circa 1910s-1930s (Boxes 2-3; 8 folders)
Series 5: Diaries, 1922-1956 (Box 2; 6 folders)
Series 6: Printed Materials, circa 1858-1966 (Boxes 2-3; 8 folders)
Series 7: Photographs, 1892-1960s (Boxes 2-3; 15 folders)
Series 8: Scrapbook, 1951 (Box 3; 2 folders)
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Biographical Materials, 1914-1971, Series 1:; (Box 1, 3, RD1; 13 folders)
  Found here are biographical sketches, an address book, a list of Faulkner's writings, an award from the Architectural League of New York, and a calendar listing social events and medical appointments. Military records from World War I include an identification card, officer's record book, awards, discharge papers, and other records. Also found here are oversized architectural drawings by Eric Gugler for Faulkner's home in Keene, New Hampshire. Materials related to the publication of Sketches From an Artist's Life, party guest lists, a list of Faulkner's medication, and an address list compiled by Mary Platt are also in this series.
  The bulk of this series has been scanned, except for the address book and the oversized archictectural drawings.
  - Address Book, circa 1964, (not scanned) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Address List, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Appointment Calendar, circa 1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Awards, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    (Architectural League of New York)
  - Biographical Sketches, circa 1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Guest Lists, circa 1960s (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - List of Writings, circa 1950s (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Medication List, 1964, (not scanned) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Military Records, 1917-1928, (also housed in Box 3) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Notes, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Sketches From an Artist's Life Materials, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Oversized Military Records, 1919, (scanned with Box 1, Folder 9) (Box 3 (sol), Folder 1)
  - Architectural Drawings, 1937, (not scanned) (Box RD, Folder 1)
    (Drawn by Eric Gugler for Faulkner's house in Keene, N.H.)
- Correspondence, 1900-1973, Series 2:; (Boxes 1; 0.5 linear feet)
  Correspondence includes letters from Faulkner's friends, family, fellow artists, and art organizations and institutions. Faulkner's letters with his parents document his 1900-1901 trip to Italy with the Thayer family. Additional family correspondence includes letters from Faulkner's brother Philip, his niece Jocelyn, his nephew Francis, and his cousin Ellen. Topics include daily activities, Faulkner's health, and family affairs and gossip. The letters also discuss other artists, such as August Saint-Gaudens, Abbott Handerson Thayer, Paul Manship, as well as the Cornish Art Colony.
  Of special interest are nine folders of correspondence with close friend and writer Witter Bynner about Faulkner's daily life in New Hampshire, travels through Europe, his artistic practice and career, opinions on artistic and literary works, his service in World War I, and Bynner's writings. Included within the correspondence with Bynner are sketches of Abbott Handerson Thayer, Rockwell Kent, Augustus Saint-Gaudens, Homer Saint-Gaudens, George de Forest Brush, Kahlil Gibran, and Mark Twain.
  Additional correspondents in this series include sculptor Frances Grimes, architect Eric Gugler, painter Leon Kroll, and museum director James Johnson Sweeney, as well as friends Elizabeth Hare, Elsie King, and Milly Knox. The letters discuss Faulkner's career, social events, family, health concerns, travel, and common friends.
  Of special interest are two postcards sent by Faulkner to "Maraine[?]" which are illustrated with pictures of Faulkner during World War I.
  Also found are letters from publishers about publishing Sketches From an Artist's Life and letters from the Library of Congress regarding a donation of Faulkner's papers.
  Some of the letters are typed transcripts and photocopies. Content has been cut out of some of the transcripts, and a few letters are annotated in pencil by an unknown hand.
  This series has been scanned in its entirety.
  - A-C, 1925-1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - William L. Bauhan, 1969-1970s (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Witter Bynner, 1903-1942, (9 folders) (Box 1, Folder 14-22)
  - Condolence Letters, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - F-K, 1949-1973 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Francis Faulkner, 1959-1963, (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 25-27)
  - Jocelyn Faulkner, 1954-1970, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 28-29)
  - Philip Faulkner, 1919-circa 1958, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 30-31)
  - Frances Grimes, 1905-1907, (4 folders) (Box 1, Folder 32-35)
  - Ann and Eric Gugler, 1960s-1970s, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 36-37)
  - Elizabeth Hare, 1918-1940s, (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 38-40)
  - Epsie King, 1950s-1966, (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 41-43)
  - Fred King, 1950s-1960s (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Milly Knox, 1942-1960s, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 45-46)
  - Leon Kroll, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - L-O, circa 1920s-1973 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Library of Congress, 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Isabel Manship, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - P-S, 1949-1966 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Parents, 1900-1902, 1963, (4 folders) (Box 1, Folder 52-55)
    (Also contains letter by Emma Thayer)
  - Rosamund Putnam, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Betty and James Kellum Smith, 1954-1957 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - James Johnson Sweeney, 1950-1960s, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 58-59)
  - Laura Sweeney, 1958-1960s (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - T-W, 1943-1966 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Writings, 1912-1966, Series 3:; (Boxes 1-2; 1.0 linear foot)
  Most of this series consists of writings by Faulkner about other artists and writers who were friends and contemporaries. There are writings on Gifford Beal, George de Forest Brush, James Earle Fraser, Harriet Hosmer, Paul Manship, Charles Adams Platt, Hiram Powers, Edward Willis Redfield, Joseph Lindon Smith, Mary Lawrence Tonetti, Mark Twain, Lawrence Grant White, and Mahonri Young.
  Other writings are about the history of New Hampshire and the Connecticut River Valley, including essays on the towns of Cornish, Walpole, and Chesterfield in New Hamphire, New Hampshire captivity narratives, stories of the Revolutionary War, and historic sites around Keene, New Hampshire. Two long essays document the history of the Dublin and Cornish art colonies, whose inhabitants included George de Forest Brush, Augustus Saint-Gaudens, and Abbott Handerson Thayer. Another essay is a history of the American Academy in Rome.
  Of special interest is an unpublished manuscript called A Neighborhood of Artists which covers the art, history, and the inhabitants of the Connecticut River Valley from the 1800s to the early 1900s. Personages discussed in the manuscript include the eighth president of Yale University Timothy Dwight, notorious criminal Stephen Burroughs, judge and playwright Royall Tyler, architect Richard Morris Hunt, the painter George Fuller, and the sculptors Henry Kirke Brown and Harriet Hosmer. Another chapter discusses the periodical Farmers Weekly Museum.
  There is a manuscript of Faulkner's memoir Swift River, published posthumously under the title Sketches of an Artist's Life.
  Other writings are about Faulkner's mural commissions including his works for the Elliot Community Hospital in Keene, New Hampshire, the National Archives, the New Hampshire Senate Chambers, and the Oregon State Capitol. Also found are essays on Amherst College, camouflage, the Hopewell Furnace in Pennsylvania, the explorer John Ledyard, walking, and witchcraft.
  Writings by others include essays about Faulkner by Leon Kroll and Paul Manship. Also found are miscellaneous essays on the camouflage section in World War I, the history of herb gardens and gardener Margaret Fitch Brewster, the scholar Olivia Rodham, mural paintings in Pennsylvania and the Villa Bosco Parasio in Rome, both written by Eric Gugler. Of special interest is a 1966 interview with Faulkner by John Bond about Augustus Saint-Gaudens.
  This series has been scanned in its entirety, except for 3 folders containing writings by others that are unrelated to art.
  - An American Sculptor: James Earle Fraser, circa 1950s (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Archives, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - [Art in New Hampshire], late 1940s (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - [Artists in the Connecticut River Valley], 1930s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Camouflage, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - The Captivity of Mrs. Johnson, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Central Square, circa 1950s (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Century Talk, circa 1950s (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Charles Adams Platt, circa 1930s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Charles Adams Platt, circa 1930s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Col. Francis Faulkner and the Battle of Lexington, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Commemorative Tribute to James Earle Fraser, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Cornish [Draft One], circa 1940s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Cornish [Draft Two], circa 1940s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Dublin [Draft One], circa 1940s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Dublin [Draft Two], circa 1940s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Dublin [Draft Three], circa 1940s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Early History of Keene and the Attack On the Fort, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Early Years of the American Academy in Rome, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Edward Willis Redfield, circa 1965 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - [Elliot Community Hospital Murals], circa 1920s-1940s (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Fasnacloich, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - George De Forest Brush, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Gifford Beal, circa 1956 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Hopewell, circa 1950s (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - The Humble Petition of Abagail Faulkner, circa 1950s (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - James Earle Fraser, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - James Earle Fraser, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - John Ledyard, circa 1950s (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Joseph Lindon Smith, circa 1956 (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Kilburn's Defense 1755, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - [Lecture to Rotary Club], 1942 (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Mark Twain in Dublin, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Mary Lawrence Tonetti, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Morelands, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Mountain Day at Amherst College, circa 1950s (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Mrs. Howe: the Fair Captive of Hinsdale, circa 1950s (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - My Early Education, circa 1947 (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Nathan Blake, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - A Neighborhood of Artists [Chapter One], circa 1930s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - A Neighborhood of Artists [Chapter Two], circa 1930s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - A Neighborhood of Artists [Chapter Three; Draft One], circa 1930s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 103)
  - A Neighborhood of Artists [Chapter Three; Draft Two], circa 1930s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 104)
  - A Neighborhood of Artists [Chapter Six], circa 1930s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 105)
  - A Neighborhood of Artists [Chapter Eight; Draft One], circa 1930s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 106)
  - A Neighborhood of Artists [Chapter Eight; Draft Two], circa 1930s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 107)
  - A Neighborhood of Artists [Chapter Nine], circa 1930s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 108)
  - A Neighborhood of Artists [Chapter Ten], circa 1930s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 109)
  - A Neighborhood of Artists [Chapter Eleven], circa 1930s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 110)
  - A Neighborhood of Artists [Chapter Twelve], circa 1930s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 111)
  - A Neighborhood of Artists [Unknown Chapter], circa 1930s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 112)
  - A Neighborhood of Artists [Notes and Outline], circa 1930s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 113)
  - A Neighborhood of Artists, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 114)
  - Notable Figures in New Hampshire History, circa 1950s (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - [Notes on Dublin], circa 1950s-1960s (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - [Notes Towards Memoirs], circa 1950s-1960s (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Objects Of Historic Interest Easily Reached From Keene, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Octomania, circa 1953 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Octomania [Draft and Notes], circa 1953 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - [On Art], circa 1940s-1950s (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - [On Hiram Powers], circa 1946 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - [On Mahouri Young], circa 1940s-1950s (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - [On Paul Manship], circa 1950s-1960s (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - [On Paul Manship (Notes)], circa 1966 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Paul Manship, circa 1966 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Paul Manship, 1885-1966, circa 1966 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - The Problems of a Mural Painter, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Research on the Murals For the Oregon State Capitol, circa 1938 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Royall Tyler, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Salma Hale, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Sketches From an Artist's Life [Chapters 1-2, 4], 1960s (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Sketches From an Artist's Life [Chapters 5-6], circa 1950s-1960s (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Sketches From an Artist's Life [Chapters 8,l0, 12], 1960s (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Sketches From an Artist's Life [Chapters 14, Fragments of Chapter 14, and 15], circa 1950s-1960s (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Sketches From an Artist's Life [Fragments of Chapters 15-16, and Chapter 17], circa 1950s-1960s (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Sketches From an Artist's Life [Fragments], 1960s (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Sketches From an Artist's Life [Outline and Drafts], 1960s (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Stephen Burroughs, circa 1950s (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Talk Before the Lions Club of Keene, New Hamphire, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Three Dublin Artists, circa 1940s-1960s (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Two Towns, circa 1940s-1960s (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - The Uncrowned Poet Laureate of Vermont, circa 1950s (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - A Visit to Keene in 1803, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Walking For Pleasure, circa 1950s (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Wax-Works and Coronets, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Wax-Works and Diadems [Draft One], circa 1950s (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Wax-Works and Diadems [Draft Two], circa 1950s (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - [Writings on George De Forest Brush], circa 1940s-1950s (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Writings by Others (Box 2)